hey guys this looks like a fun one it
says find the area of the square now
we're told that each of the rectangles
inside of the square have equal areas if
you're going to try this on your own
pause it right now cuz I'm going to
solve it in 3 2 1 since the areas of all
five rectangles are equal to each other
that means that each of these rectangles
has an area that's 1 of the entire
Square so if I make the square something
like X by X the entire square is going
to be x^2 and then each of these
rectangles would be x^2 / 5 so that
feels like a pretty strong first step
for the next step out of all of these
rectangles the blue one is the only one
that has X entirely as one of its sides
so let's focus on that one we already
know that the height is X let's call the
base B we know that the base of B times
the height of X is going to be equal to
the area x^2 5 and I want to know what
is B in terms of X so let's divide both
sides of the equation by X on the left
hand side these will cancel so we just
have B and on the right hand side you
can think of x^2 as x * X and then one
of these X's will cancel from top and
bottom so that means B is equal to X
over 5 or 1 x so let's change this B to
1/5 X and the same thing for the top it
will also be/ X and now let's bring back
the rest of our Square each side of this
square is equal to X so if this blue
portion is 1/5 X that means that the
orange portion is going to be 4 fths x
and now we have all the parts of this
orange rectangle so let's focus on that
and then once again base time height
will equal the area so we know that the
base of 4S x * the height of 3 will
equal the area of x^2 5 so on the left
hand side let's write this as a single
fraction on top we can do 4 * x * 3
which gives us 12x and on bottom we just
have the 5 and this is still equal to
x^2 over 5 next we can multiply both
sides by 5 overx and we are allowed to
divide by X here because we know X is
not equal to zero on the left hand side
these two fives cancel each other out
and these two x's cancel each other out
all we have left is 12 and on the right
hand side these two fives cancel each
other each other out and x^2 overx is
just X so now we know that 12 is equal
to X going back to our original Square X
was the side lengths of the square so
this square is a 12x 12 square so to
find the area of this square is just
going to be 12 squar and 12 squ is equal
to 144 and let's give it a label of
square units and this is the answer to
our question the given square has an
area of 144 square units let's put a box
around it how exciting if you guys want
to try more of these geometry challenge
problems I have this page on mat.com
there's a link in the description